Deepa Tilwani

VISITING RESEARCH INTERN @ AIISC

1/717, Moti vihar colony, Ramnagar, Pushkar road, Ajmer, Rajasthan, India

□ (+1)803-477-4526 | ■ tilwanideepa2@gmail.com | □ Deepa-Tilwani | □ deepa-tilwani-b758551a0/

Summary.

Current Research Intern at AI Institute University of South Carolina, working on Autism detection based on ECG data. I had an experience as a Data Science intern and applied various techniques of machine learning for extracting information and building model accordingly. Open for collaboration research work in the field of data science, machine learning or artificial intelligence. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Research Interests

Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Brain Computer Interface, Neuroscience, Artificial Intelligence for Health Care.

Work Experience

Visiting Research Intern

Columbia, SC, USA

Al Institute, University of South Carolina

September 2021 - Present

- · Adopting, utilizing and developing new approaches, methodologies for Lesion Mapping and classification in Aphasia.
- Actively participating in projects in research group at Al Institute.
- Building and implementing architecture road-maps for next generation Artificial Intelligence solutions for our collaborators.

Remote Research Intern

Remote-Columbia, SC, USA

Al Institute, University of South Carolina

October 2020 - August 2021

- Planning and executing challenging technical problems.
- Organizing, analysing, pre-processing of ECG signals, using signal processing techniques.
- Designing pipeline for Autism likelihood in infants using Machine Learning.

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Jaipur, Rajasthan, India

THE LNM INSTITUTE OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

August. 2019 - Present

- Assisting and evaluating B.Tech students in Computer Network labs.
- Helping students to implementing queries in MySQL lab.
- Assisting and evaluating B.Tech students in MySQL lab work.

Data Science Intern Remote

The Sparks Foundation Aug. 2020 - Sept. 2020

- Pre-Processing of the data set provided using numpy and pandas libraries in python.
- Extracting valuable information from data set.
- · Worked on creating models using supervised machine learning techniques.

Education

The LNM Institute of Information Technology

Jaipur, Rajasthan, India

2019 - Pursuing

M.TECH. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

• CGPA: 7.42

Govt. Women Engineering College (GWECA)

Ajmer, Rajasthan, India

B.TECH. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

2014 - 2018

• Percentage: 67.4

Queen Mary's Girls School

Ajmer, Rajasthan, India

INTERMEDIATE - 12TH

2013-2014

Percentage: 68.4Queen Mary's Girls School

Ajmer, Rajasthan, India

HIGH SCHOOL - 10TH

2011-2012

• CGPA: 7.2

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL

Sept 2020 2nd Prize, LINZ Ars Festival -BR41N.IO HACKATHON Linz July 2020 **2nd Prize**, BR41N.IO: Brain-Computer Interface Designers Hackathon Austria

DOMESTIC

2016 **GWECA** 1st Place, Presentation on AR and VR Technology 2015 3rd Place, Toast to Code- C Language **GWECA** 2012 Silver Prize, National Science Olympiad Aimer

Projects

Lesion mapping and Classification in Aphasia using Structural MRI's.

Columbia, SC, USA

VISITING RESEARCH INTERN

RESEARCH INTERN

January 2022 - Present

Analysing damages caused by Aphasia in left hemisphere of brain using T2 weighted images.

Remote- Al Institute University of

South Carolina

Remote-Linz

Predicting likelihood of Autism in infants using ECG's.

Oct. 2020 - Present

• Analyzed ECG data-set of infants for early detection of Autism.

• Pre-processing, feature extraction and developing models using Machine Learning and Deep Learning algorithms.

Data Analysis of ECoG Data

HACKATHON PROJECT Sept. 2020

· Analyzing an ECoG data-set having the data of rock paper scissor hand movements or hand-poses from an epilepsy person in order to optimize pre-processing, feature extraction and classification algorithms. Compared machine learning algorithms results with state-of-the-art algorithms.

Motor Imagery EEG BCI Data Analysis

Remote-Austria

BR41N.IO Brain Computer Interface Designers Hackathon Project

· Analyzed a motor imagery BCI data-set from a chronic stroke patient in order to optimize pre-processing, feature extraction and classification algorithms. Compared results with state-of-the-art algorithms.

Freelancer Website GWFCA

MAJOR B.TECH PROJECT Dec 2017- April 2018

- · Website for final year project submission.
- Where user or freelancers registers themselves to search or request needed jobs of their interest.
- Any project or job can also be added by the companies who are looking for respective candidates who can willingly complete the projects provided.

Presentations _

Presented Paper> 20-21 MARCH,2021

INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON DATA DRIVEN COMPUTING AND IOT (DDCIOT-2021)

GEETANJALI INSTITUTE OF TECHNICAL

· A Comparative Study and Tool to Early Predict Diabetes using Various Machine and Deep Learning Based Techniques. Authors: Shrusti Porwal, Chintal Patel, Deepa Tilwani, Shrikrishn Bansal. Paper id 41

Skills_

Back-end MySQL Front-end HTML5,CSS

Tools and Technologies C, Python, LaTeX, Machine Learning, Matlab, Digital Signal Processing

> Languages Hindi, English

Certifications and Training's _

Data Analytics Virtual Training Program

Ouantium

VIRTUAL TRAINING

CERTIFICATION

Sept. 2020

· Analysed data of a daily store.

Fundamentals of Scalable Data Science

IBM

July. 2020

· Introductory Course on Data Science by IBM

Python for Everybody Specialization

Coursera

Certification April. 2020

• Specialization Course for Python.

Indian Space and Research Organization

Jodhpur, Rajasthan, India

SUMMER TRAINING PROGRAM- WEB DEVELOPER

Jun. 2017 - July. 2017

• Implemented back end using MySql which is communicating with client, along with two other team members who wrote the php logic's and designed front end.

Government Women Engineering College

Ajmer, Rajasthan, India

FEST WEBSITE DEVELOPER Jan. 2016 - Mar. 2016

• Designed website with other team members for college technical fest with a separate login portal for students and organizers.